Guide to the Clarence L. Houghton papers, 1883-1923.
Houghton, Clarence L. papers, 1883-1923.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Clarence L. Houghton papers, 1883-1923.
899
Clarence L. Houghton
.4 cubic ft.
Correspondence, photographs, a diary fragment, programs, articles, newspaper clippings, and other printed materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers of Clarence L. Houghton, an Ithaca newspaperman, pertaining to local events and organizations.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Newspaperman.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Programs, articles, newspaper clippings, and other printed materials pertaining to local events and organizations, including material relating to the Ithaca Cycle Club (1896-1903), the Thomas School of Aviation, the League of American Wheelmen and its good road movement (1897-1901), the temperance movement, public schools, Masons Hobasco Lodge, the Ithaca Conservatory of Music, Cornell University, and local churches; also, photographs of Ithaca including Rogues Harbor Inn Lansing, Cayuga Hose Company, Ithaca High School Band, Cornell University, and a murder case in Tompkins County; a letter regarding the sale of The Weekly Ithacan (1917), another describing St. Nazaire and the water-supply problems of the American Army (1919); and one from William H. Jessup, Poughkeepsie, to Houghton, telling of Edgar Apgar's role in recognizing the political potentialities of Grover Cleveland; and a diary fragment (1865), Williamsport, Pennsylvania.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Houghton, Clarence L.; Apgar, Edgar.; Cleveland, Grover, 1837-1908.; Jessup, William H.; Cornell University--Description--Views.; Ithaca Conservatory of Music--Description--Views.; Ithaca Cycle Club (Ithaca, N.Y.); League of American Wheelmen.; Thomas School of Aviation (Ithaca, N.Y.)
Titles:
Weekly Ithacan.
Subjects:
Schools--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Cycling.; Churches--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Murder--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Temperance.
Places:
United States--Armed Forces--Sanitary affairs.; United States--Politics and government.; Tompkins County (N.Y.)--History.; Ithaca (N.Y.)--Description--Views.; Ithaca (N.Y.)--Societies, etc.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Diaries.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence, 1901-1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Reception of Admiral Dewey, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Churches (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Cornelliana, 1902-1919 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Ithaca Conservatory of Music, 1912, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Ithaca Cycle Club, 1896-1903 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Ithaca Cycle Club newsclippings, 1896-1897 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Ithaca Daily Journal Annual Greeting of the Carrier Boys, 1889-1899 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Ithaca High School programs, 1887-1898 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Ithaca; Ithaca organizations, 1914-1928 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Ithaca Public Schools, 1912-1924 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Ithaca Savings Bank (list of trustees), ca. 1916 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Knights of Pythias, 1883-1923 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Methodist Episcopal Church, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Miscellany, 1897-1916 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Newsclippings (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Rotary Club, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Thomas School of Aviation (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Includes photographs of Thomas Aviation, a brochure for the aviation school, and photos of Thomas Morse aircraft.
- Judge Sweetland (article draft) (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Temperance, 1911-1923 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Transportation, 1916-1919 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Photographs
  - Ithacans (for newspaper articles) (Box 2)
  - Cornell (Box 2)
  - Murder case
    - "Alpha Sigma Phi lodge, Rockledge, on the cliffs above Fall Creek Gorge, where Fether was arrested" (Box 2)
    - "View of Rockledge" (Box 2)
    - "Home of Crance family" (Box 2)
    - "View of Tompkins County jail" (Box 2)
    - "Another view, Tompkins County jail" (Box 2)
    - "District Attorney Arthur G. Adams (with straw hat) discussing case with Edward Crance, father of dead girl" (Box 2)
    - "Office of Sheriff" (Box 2)
    - "Sheriff Charles Green" (Box 2)
- Printed material
  - American Education, 1912 (Box 2)
  - List of Registered Voters of Tompkins County, 1912 (Box 2)
  - The Cornell Countryman, 1914 (Box 2)
  - The New Success, 1919 (Box 2)
  - Current History, 1928 (Box 2)
  - Fifty Games of Cards, 1931 (Box 2)
- Miscellany
  - Badge: 47th Annual Reunion, 15th and 50th Regiments, Engineer Brigade Army of Potomac (Box 2)
  - Plaque: "5 1900 Sidepath Tompkins County" (Box 2)